Finding Aid for Perry Bullard papers, 1969-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical files
  - 1973-1990
    - Geake Plan for Welfare Cuts, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Halfway House in Ann Arbor, 1989 (Box 53)
    - Holiday Moratorium, (HB2901), 1987 (Box 53)
    - Housing Trust Fund, 1983 (Box 53)
    - Industrial Policy, 1980-1983 (Box 53)
    - Job Training, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Judge Daner Investigation, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Land Ethic Education, 1981-1982 (Box 53)
    - Low-Level Radioactive Waste in Michigan, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Major Issues in Michigan Politics, 1983 (Box 53)
    - Medical Power of Attorney (HB4175), 1983 (Box 53)
    - Medical Power of Attorney (HB4883), 1985 (Box 53)
    - Medical Power of Attorney (HB4647), 1987; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Medical Power of Attorney (HB4016), 1990; 3 folders (Box 53)
    - Medicare Supplemental Insurance (HB4779, HB4780), 1990 (Box 53)
    - Museum Property (HB4752), 1992 (Box 53)
    - Nuclear Arms Freeze, 1981-1985 (Box 53)
    - Nuclear Free Zone, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Occupational Safety, 1984 (Box 53)
    - Pit Bulls (HB4897, SB269, SB270), 1988 (Box 53)
    - Political Rights, 1981 (Box 53)
    - Post-Majority Child Support (HB5287), 1990 (Box 53)
    - Prison Construction Committee, 1985; 5 folders (Box 53)
    - Public Employee Pensions in Divorce Proceedings (HB5602-5610), 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 53)
    - Recording Equipment in Contested Case Hearings (HB4208), 1985 (Box 54)
    - Rent Control (SB583), 1988 (Box 54)
    - Res Gestae Repeal (HB4246, HB4394, SB119), 1984-1987; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Retired Probate Judges (HB4551), 1987 (Box 54)
    - Retraction on Lawmakers' Salary Reports, 1983 (Box 54)
    - Shoplifting (HB5591, HB5592, HB5593), 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Small Claims (HB4776), 1984-1991; 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Smith-Bullard Tax Plan, 1980 (Box 54)
    - Solar Energy Tax Incentives (HB4622), 1983 (Box 54)
    - Solar Energy Tax Credit Renewal, 1986 (Box 54)
    - South Africa Divestiture
      - Photographs, undated (Box 54)
      - Clippings and Information (Box 54)
      - Anti-Apartheid, 1979-1984; 2 folders (Box 54)
      - Background, 1979-1981 (Box 54)
      - Bullard Legislation Plans, 1980-1982 (Box 54)
      - Divestiture, 1980-1984 (Box 54)
      - Divestiture Reports, 1977-1981 (Box 54)
      - History of Legislative Efforts, 1976-1980 (Box 54)
      - International Monetary Fund Loans, 1983 (Box 54)
      - International Political Rights (Box 54)
      - Michigan Trade, 1983 (Box 54)
      - Pension Divestiture, 1980-1983 (Box 54)
      - U.S. Congress Legislation, 1983 (Box 54)
      - Legislation (Box 54)
      - Bank Loans (HB5446), 1980 (Box 54)
      - Bills and Amendments, 1979 (Box 54)
      - Condone Human Rights Violations (HB4831), 1980 (Box 54)
      - Correctional Institutions Amendments, (HB4889), 1983 (Box 54)
      - Elliot Larsen Civil Rights Act Amendments (HB4553), 1981-1982 (Box 54)
      - Mandela Citizenship Resolution, 1983 (Box 54)
      - Pension Divestiture (HB4516), 1983 (Box 54)
      - University of Michigan Debate, 1982-1983 (Box 54)
      - University of Michigan Compliance, 1983 (Box 54)
    - Spousal Rape (HB4834 HB4835), 1987-1988 (Box 54)
    - State Accident Fund, 1982 (Box 54)
    - Student Activity Fee Uses (SB658), 1984 (Box 54)
    - Surrogate Parenting
      - (HB4753), 1987 (Box 54)
      - (SB228), 1984 (Box 54)
      - (HB5178 SB100), 1989 (Box 54)
      - ACLU Challenge, 1988 (Box 54)
      - Testimonies, 1987-1989 (Box 54)
    - Tax Increase Speech, 1983 (Box 55)
    - Ticket Quotas (HB4538), 1987 (Box 55)
    - Toxic Substances, 1980-1983 (Box 55)
    - Trust Funds for Legal Aid, 1983 (Box 55)
    - Truth-in-Testing, 1981 (Box 55)
    - Union-Labor Relations, 1983 (Box 55)
    - Vehicle Color Registration (HB5725), 1986 (Box 55)
    - Video Display Terminals, 1983 (Box 55)
    - Videotaping Children's Testimonies for Court in Child Abuse Cases (HB4033), 1985 (Box 55)
    - Vietnam Veterans, 1987 (Box 55)
    - Voter's Choice-Proposal C, 1984; 2 folders (Box 55)
    - War Resistance, 1985 (Box 55)
    - Weapons Training (HB4124), 1985 (Box 55)
    - Workmen's Compensation (HB4947, HB4948), 1977-1979; 5 folders (Box 55)
    - Wrongful Death (HB4988), 1984 (Box 55)
    - Youth Job Corps (HB5507), 1984 (Box 55)
  - 1977-1992
    - Animal Welfare
      - Animal Abuse, 1990-1992 (Box 56)
      - Animal Fighting and Medical Research, 1989-1991 (Box 56)
    - Arts Legislation, 1980-1987 (Box 56)
    - Asbestos in Schools, 1979; 1987-1988 (Box 56)
    - Capital Punishment, 1986-1989 (Box 56)
    - Child Care, 1986-1988
      - Correspondence, Congressional Record (Box 56)
      - Organizations (Box 56)
      - Publications (Box 56)
      - Reports and Testimonies (Box 56)
    - Civil Rights Pre-emption, 1985 (Box 56)
    - Community Dispute Resolution Centers, 1987 (Box 56)
    - Consumer Privacy Legislation, 1987-1988 (Box 56)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 56)
    - Court Financing, 1983 (Box 56)
    - Drug Prevention Through Education (Box 56)
    - Foster Parent Immunity, 1987 (Box 56)
    - Funeral Home Practices (Box 56)
    - Insanity Defense, 1982-1983; 1986 (Box 56)
    - Judgeships, 1992 (Box 56)
    - Juvenile Justice
      - Juvenile Delinquency Public Hearing, 2/9/1987 (Box 56)
      - Juvenile Justice Code Revision (Box 56)
      - Juvenile Justice Code Revision Subcommittee, 1985 (Box 56)
    - Labor Unions, 1980-1981 (Box 56)
    - Legislative Service Bureau, 1991 (Box 56)
    - Mandatory Retirement of Tenured Professors, 1991 (Box 56)
    - Marital Rape, 1983 (Box 56)
    - Marriage Disability Bill, 1985-1986 (Box 56)
    - Media Libel Bill, 1988 (Box 56)
    - Medical Legislation
      - Determination of Death, 1987-1991 (Box 57)
      - Do Not Resuscitate Procedures Act, 1992 (Box 57)
      - Nurse Testimonial Immunity, 1986 (Box 57)
      - Organ Transplant, 1985 (Box 57)
      - Physician Discipline, 1989-1990 (Box 57)
    - Medical Waste, 1988 (Box 57)
    - Medicare Mandatory Assignment
      - Analysis, Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 57)
      - Determination of Allowable Charge, 1988-1989 (Box 57)
      - Comparison of States' Prevailing Charge, 1988 (Box 57)
      - Data, 1987-1990 (Box 57)
      - Federal Law and Legislation, 1990 (Box 57)
      - Michigan State Medical Society Information, 1989-1991 (Box 57)
      - Press, 1989-1990 (Box 57)
      - Testimony (Box 57)
    - Mental Health, 1991 (Box 57)
    - Michigan Dept. of State Police (Box 57)
    - Military Spending, 1982-1986 (Box 57)
    - National Guard
      - Central America, 1985-1987 (Box 57)
      - Honduras, 1987 (Box 57)
      - Michigan State Defense Force, 1986-1987 (Box 57)
    - Nuclear Waste Disposal, 1981 (Box 57)
    - Open Meetings Act, 1977-1979 (Box 57)
    - Petitioning in Shopping Centers, 1985-1986 (Box 57)
    - Plant Closings
      - Correspondence and Reports, 1981-1984 (Box 57)
      - Plant Closing Conference, 10/23/1987 (Box 57)
      - Publications (Box 57)
      - Correspondence Opposition (selection) (Box 57)
      - Correspondence Support (selection) (Box 57)
      - Background Material (Box 57)
    - Prison Escape Sentencing (Box 58)
    - Privacy Rights, 1980-1983 (Box 58)
    - Property Reverter Legislation, 1988 (Box 58)
    - Prosecutors Right to Appeal Beyond Acquittal (Box 58)
    - School Finance Reform, 1989 (Box 58)
    - Small Claims
      - Correspondence, 1977-1992 (Box 58)
      - How to Sue Publications (Box 58)
      - Legislation, 1974-1976 (Box 58)
      - Studies of Michigan Courts (Box 58)
    - South Africa
      - Briefing Book, 1985; 2 folders (Box 58)
      - Divestment Laws (Box 58)
      - Press (Box 58)
    - State Accident Fund
      - General, 1983-1987 (Box 58)
      - Research Materials (Box 58)
      - Proposed Amendments (Box 58)
      - Court Decision (Box 58)
      - Correspondence (Box 58)
    - Strip Searches, 1983 (Box 58)
    - Surrogate Parenting, 1987-1988 (Box 58)
    - Taxation
      - Tax Sales, 1987-1992 (Box 58)
      - Taxation of Insurers, 1987 (Box 58)
    - Tobacco (Box 58)
    - Toxic Art Supplies
      - Legislation, 1987-1989 (Box 58)
      - Comparison to other states (Box 58)
      - Press, 1988 (Box 58)
      - Reports (Box 58)
    - Video Censorship, 1984; 1987-1988 (Box 58)
    - University of Michigan
      - Racism, 1987 (Box 58)
      - Student Code, 1984; 1990-1991 (Box 58)
- Legislative files of House Judiciary chair Bob Traxler and of committee counsels Bruce A. Timmons and Greg Kershuls
  Received with the Bullard papers were materials which he received from his predecessor of the House Judiciary Committee Bob Traxler and from the counsels who served the committee Bruce A. Timmons and Greg Kershuls. Most of these files relate to revision of the Uniform Controlled Substances Act in 1971-1972.
  - HB4882 Revised Uniform Controlled Substances Act, 1971-1972 (Box 59)
  - HB4882 Revised Uniform Controlled Substances Act, 1971-1972 (Box 60)
  - HB5886 Alcohol Treatment, 1972 (Box 60)
  - HB4008 Substance Abuse Assistance, 1973 (Box 60)
  - HB5886 Alcohol Treatment, 1972 (Box 61)
  - Various legislation (Box 61)
- Michigan Law Revision Commission
  Also received with the Bullard papers were files of the Michigan Law Revision Commission, 1969-1972. These were probably files maintained by Bruce A. Timmons.
  - Subject files, 1969-1972 (Box 62)
    (probably files of Judiciary Committee counsel Bruce Timmons)
  - Subject files, 1969-1972 (Box 63)
  - Subject files, 1969-1972 (Box 64)
- Political and campaign materials
  The Political and Campaign materials series largely concerns Bullard's election and re-election campaigns. Included are campaign literature of Bullard and his opponent, and strategies on running a campaign. Also of interest are material relating to the effort to have Bullard and other colleagues recalled from office in 1983.
  - Democratic Organizations of Michigan (Box 65)
  - Recall effort against Bullard and other state legislators, 1983 (Box 65)
  - Campaign miscellaneous, 1978-1988 (Box 65)
- Publicity. Speeches, Clippings, etc.
  The Publicity, Speeches, Clippings series includes press releases (1972-1992), newsletters sent to his constituents, letters he wrote to the editor of newspapers, transcripts of responses he made to television editorials, and political speeches and addresses within the legislature. There are also miscellaneous clippings with articles about Bullard.
  - Press releases, undated; 1972-1992 (Box 66)
  - Newsletters, 1975-1992 (Box 66)
  - Guides, handbooks, and other published material distributed by Bullard's office (Box 66)
  - Speeches, undated; 1975-1989 (Box 67)
  - Letters to the editor, television editorial responses, miscellaneous clippings (Box 67)
- Personal
  The Personal series is small and includes biographical materials, a few folders, and a listing of the legislation sponsored by Bullard. This listing only goes to the mid-1970s.
  - Biographical material, including early lists (1970s) of legislation sponsored (Box 67)
  - Photographs (Box 67)